Inter-American Music Festival Foundation Papers
Music Division, Library of Congress
Guides to Special Collections in the Music Division of the Library of Congress
Inter-American Music Festival Foundation Papers 1961-1981
ML31.I57
Inter-American Music Festival Foundation
200 items 2 containers 1 linear foot
Music Division Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
This collection contains concert programs, publicity materials, clippings and correspondence from the nearly 25-year history of the Inter-American Music Festival Foundation. The Foundation was organized by the Inter-American Music Council in 1958 under the auspices of the Pan American Union "to promote closer relations and understanding among the American republics by recognizing and stimulating the development of music of the Americas." The foundation's concerts introduced the finest composers and performers from Latin America, the Caribbean, United States, and Canada. Harold Boxer, chief, Music Branch, Voice of America; Guillermo Espinosa, chief, Music Division, Organization of American States; and Harold Spivacke, chief, Music Division, Library of Congress were responsible for incorporating the foundation in 1965.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically therein.
People
Boxer, Harold--Correspondence.; Espinosa, Guillermo, 1905-1990--Correspondence.; Spivacke, Harold, 1904-1977.
Organizations
Inter-American Music Council.; Inter-American Music Festival Foundation--Archives.; Inter-American Music Festival Foundation.; Inter-American Music Festival Foundation.; Organization of American States.; Pan American Union.
Subjects
Concert programs--America.; Music festivals--America.
Titles
Papers of the Inter-American Music Festival Foundation, 1961-1981
Form/Genre
Clippings (information artifacts).; Correspondence.; Programs.
Administrative Information
Accruals
No further accruals are expected.
Related Material
The Library of Congress, Motion Picture, Broadcasting and Recorded Sound Division holds recordings for many of the Inter-American Music Festival concerts. Many of the concerts have been cataloged and are searchable in the Library's online catalog.
Access and Restrictions
The Inter-American Music Festival Foundation Papers are open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Performing Arts Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Certain restrictions to use or copying of materials may apply.
Agency History
The Inter-American Music Festival Foundation was organized in 1958 by the Inter-American Music Council under the auspices of the Pan American Union "to promote closer relations and understanding among the American republics by recognizing and stimulating the development of music of the Americas." The foundation's concerts introduced the finest composers and performers from Latin America, the Caribbean, United States and Canada.
Scope and Content Note
This collection contains concert programs, publicity materials, clippings, and correspondence from the nearly 25-year history of the Inter-American Music Festival Foundation. Harold Boxer, chief of the Music Branch of Voice of America, Guillermo Espinosa, chief of the Music Division of the Organization of American States, and Harold Spivake, chief of the Music Division of the Library of Congress were responsible for incorporating the foundation in 1965. The collection contains correspondence from Espinosa and Boxer, among others. The Library lacks materials for festivals one and eleven.
Arrangement of the Inter-American Music Festival Foundation Papers
The Inter-American Music Festival Foundation Papers are organized chronologically.
http://lccn.loc.gov/2006568179
Container List
- Festivals, 1961-1981 (Box 1-2)
  - Festival 2, 1961 Apr. 22-30, Washington, D.C. (Box-folder 1/1)
  - Festival 3, 1965 May 7-12, Washington, D.C. (Box-folder 1/2)
  - Festival 4, 1968 June 19-30, Washington, D.C. (Box-folder 1/3)
  - Festival 4, 1968 June 19-30, Washington, D.C. (Box-folder 1/4)
  - Festival 5, 1971 May 18-30, Washington, D.C. (Box-folder 1/5)
  - Festival 5, 1971 May18-30, Washington, D.C. (Box-folder 1/6)
  - Festival 6, 1974 Apr. 30-May 5, Washington, D.C. (Box-folder 2/1)
  - Festival 7, 1976 May 17-24, Washington, D.C. (Box-folder 2/2)
  - Festival 8, 1977 May 2-7, Washington, D.C. (Box-folder 2/3)
  - Festival 9, 1978 May 3-13, Washington, D.C. (Box-folder 2/4)
  - Festival 10, 1979 May 7-12, Washington, D.C. (Box-folder 2/5)
  - Festival 12, 1981 May 8-14, Washington, D.C. (Box-folder 2/6)